HEATHER CHURCH

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

1069 East Millcreek Way, Millcreek, Ut 84106

☐ heatherlchurch11@gmail.com

in www.linkedin.com/in/heatherlchurch

https://github.com/hchurch11

Skills/Traits:

- Quick to Learn
- Punctual
- Analytical
- Natural Leader and collaborator
- Visual and Creative thinker
- Adaptable
- Excellent Verbal and Written Communication
- Passionate
- A "do-er"
- Innovative
- Successfully learn through trial and error
- Organized

Developer Skills:

- html5,
- css3
 - css Media queries
 - flexbox/css grid
- bootstrap
- javascript ES6
 - NodeJS/npm
 - ExpressJS
 - mongooseJS
- React
- AJAX/jquery
- ait, GitHub
- VS Code/Terminal
- API
- Hosting (Netlify)
- Google Firebase
- mongoDB/NoSQL

Profile

With over a decade of work experience as a teacher and musician that includes mid-high level positions such as Director and Manager, I am not new to the work force or career success. However, I am new to the tech industry, but I'm ready to use skills from previous experiences to enhance my new career as a Front End Developer. With having a certificate in Frontend development, and soon to have a React Certification, I'm looking for an entry level job with titles that include, "Junior," "Front End Developer," or "React."

Education

University of Denver, Denver, Co

Percussion Performance Certificate, 2016 Master of Music in Percussion Performance, 2015

University of North Dakota, Grand Forks, ND

Bachelor of Music in Music Education, 2012

Utah Teaching License, 721177

K-12 Music - exp. 06/2022

Coding Education

SheCodes Workshops, Online

React Certificate, (in progress)
Front End Development Certificate, 2020
Intro to Coding Certificate, 2020

Experience

Percussion Instructor at Alta High School, Sandy, Ut - present

Grow students' musical skill and ability through effective teaching techniques, rehearsals, and demonstrations. Placed second in percussion at the Timpanogos Invitation Marching Band Competition.

Front Ensemble Caption-head at Ogden High School, Ogden, Ut - present

Grow students' musical skill and ability through effective teaching techniques, rehearsals, and demonstrations. Placed third in percussion at the Timpanogos Invitation Marching Band Competition.

Percussion Substitute at Utah Symphony, Salt Lake City, Ut -2019 - present

Perform with the Utah Symphony | Utah Opera when extra percussionists are needed.

Freelance Musician and Teacher at Self-Employed, Salt Lake City, Ut -2012 - present

Perform and collaborate with various orchestras and small ensembles throughout Arizona, Colorado, and Utah. Toured with the Denver Philharmonic in China in the summer of 2016. Manage, recruit, and teach private percussion lessons to young musicians.

$\label{eq:percussion} \textbf{\textit{Percussion Director}} \ \textit{at Juan Diego Catholic High School, Draper, Ut} - 2019 \text{--} 20$

Established a curriculum for beginning, intermediate, and advanced percussion at both the high school and middle school levels. Directed drum line and steel band. Founded a program called "Music in the Halls" to promote my programs and lead to doubling the number of students. Collaborated in performances for mass and other religious events. Achieved superior ratings in percussion performances at competition.

Percussion Manager at Aspen Music Festival and School, Aspen, Co - 2019 (seasonal)

Created a percussion order for all percussion instrumental needs for the summer festival. Managed a team and schedules. Assigned tasks to organize and move equipment to ensure that performances and performers had all the instruments they needed. Worked closely with festival faculty, guest artists, and students.

In your company, I will:

- Use all my past knowledge and experience to be an employee that can follow directions, but also use creative problem solving when appropriate.
- Code within company standards to bring designs and ideas to life.
- Prioritize projects and tasks to ensure timely, clean, and successful results.
- Continue learning to keep up with the fast changing world of tech and to ensure all my knowledge is up to current standards of languages and technologies.
- Embrace exciting and fastpaced opportunities that will sharpen my skills, drive innovation, and play an internal role in growing your brand.

Percussion/Music Teacher at Salty Cricket, West Valley, Ut — 2018 - 19

Established a daytime and after school music program at Wallace Stegner Academy. Implemented curriculum enhanced lesson plans that educated students about the fundamentals of music on the Kindergarten through Eighth grade level. Taught an intermediate and advanced percussion class, beginning music class, and advanced orchestra to children in first through sixth grade after school program. Used music to teach life skills and to promote social change.

Percussionist at CINQ Percussion, Salt Lake City, Ut - 2018 - 2019

Performed outreach concerts around the valley to promote music education in schools and the community. Featured artist at the 2018 Utah Arts Festival.

Percussion Director at Tooele High School, Tooele, Ut -2018 - 19

Grew students' musical skill and ability through effective teaching techniques, rehearsals, and demonstrations. Placed third at the State Marching Band Competition.

${\it Chair\ of\ Events}$ at Young Professionals of the Colorado Symphony, Denver, Co - 2017 - 19

Created, hosted, and managed events and programs to involve the community in fundraising for symphony support and to get young professionals more active in the artistic involvement.

Festival Coordinator at Mile High Drum & Percussion Festival, Englewood, Co - 2018

Initiated sponsor requests, created sponsor receipts, and documented items donated for the records of both parties. Created festival schedule and assisted with artist logistics and gear distribution.

Nanny at Self-employed, Denver, Co - 2016-2018

Negotiated and wrote working contracts, created invoices, produced progress reports, executed schedules, and maintained direct and honest communication. Participated and organized activities in art, music, language development, science discovery, and nature.

Teaching Assistant at University of Denver, Denver, Co -2013-15

Directed percussion ensemble rehearsals and managed percussion studios and inventory. Engaged in programming and administrative duties. Created purchase requests and generated systems to help better organize studio spaces.

Director at Prescott Marimba Camp, Prescott, Az - 2013

Founded, directed, and organized a week-long marimba camp for middle and high school students.

Assistant Director at Prescott High School, Prescott, Az = 2012

Assisted in the direction of various music ensembles. Made detailed lesson plans, logged progress, and assisted in managing budgets.

Audio Technician at University of North Dakota, Grand Forks, ND - 2008-12

Recorded student recitals, chamber concerts, and guest artist recitals. Created cd's and digital recording copies to be filed for reference in the music library. Managed the stage and helped musicians with any pre or post recital needs.